Philip Straw

Mobile: 07794868397

Email: philcstraw@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://philcstraw.github.io/Portfolio/

Github: https://github.com/philcstraw

Games

Little Big Planet, Little Big Planet 2, Tear Away, Dreams, Man of Medan, Jigsaw Jumble, Dynoball, Linking

Game designer, software engineer and self-taught programmer with up to 10 years of game industry experience. I am an effective communicator and collaborator with great attention to detail and a drive for tackling ambitious problems. I thrive on delivering goals to high standards and within challenger constraints. I have been responsible for content design and implementation for multiple industry-leading and award winning AAA games.

Work History

Kythera AI Unity Developer | Unity, C#, C++, PC, Consoles, Mobile

Dec 2021 - June 2024

- Responsible for the development and management of a plugin that enables Unity's scripting system to interact with Kythera's proprietary C++ AI engine.
- Maintained code in Unity and Kythera to facilitate interoperability between C# and C++.
- Built Unity components and user interfaces that interact with the C++ library.
- Designed and built levels to test and demonstrate Kythera's AI features.
- Optimised debug rendering to achieve real-time frame rates.
- Liaised with clients to address queries, gaining a better understanding of their requirements and constraints in order to help them achieve their goals.
- Collaborating with other engineers to revise and improve implementations.
- Wrote comprehensive documentation and tutorials for the plugin's available features.

Independent Developer | Unity, C#, Android

2019 - 2021

- Worked on 3 mobile games on all aspects of game creation from prototype to completion, including gameplay design, difficulty balancing, art, UI, UX, audio and asset management.
- Wrote shaders and developed custom UI tools to facilitate experimentation and faster iterations times.
- Doing performance optimisations for Android devices.
- Running tests for multiple Android devices to ensure maximum compatibility.
- Published 2 of the finished games to the Android play store, and pushing updates post release.
- Google AdMob and in-app purchase integration.

Super Massive Games Contract Level Designer | Unreal Engine 4, in-house tools

2018 - 2019

- Level designer on Super Massive Game's branching narrative game Man of Medan.
- Added motion captured animations, creating cinematic interactions and responsible for overall maintenance for a number of levels.
- Authoring cameras to achieve a cinematic feel that invokes tension, fear and mystery.
- Helped with localisation, bug fixing, network testing and participated in peer reviewed feedback.

Sony Media Molecule Level Designer | in-house tools, PlayStation 3, PlayStation 4, PlayStation Vita 2011 – 2018

- Worked closely with directors to implement levels and gameplay that spanned multiple genres and targeted all age groups across 3 of their published games.
- Responsible for cinematic and tutorial design.
- Collaborated with team members across all disciplines to aid in the creation of customer facing tools for user generated content.
- Conducted user tests and implemented feedback.
- Quality assurance test for gameplay, networking and user generated content tools.

Tools and Frameworks	Technical Skills	Soft Skills
Gameplay design and balancing Level design Event scripting AI behaviour authoring Visual scripting Cinematic design Environmental art Software engineering Performance analysis and optimisation Debugging Documentation and tutorials	C# C++, C++/CLI LUA GLSL, HLSL OpenGL, Vulcan Unity Unreal Engine 4, Blueprints Github Perforce Source Tree Jira Confluence Dear ImGui, WPF, Winforms Visual Studio Render Doc	Good communication Innovative Proactive Excellent time management AGILE practices Works well under pressure Self-motivated Critical thinker Attention to detail Eager to learn Friendly Mentoring

Programming Projects

Game Engine C++

- 3D rigidbody physics Collision detection Spatial partitioning Assimp SDK file import and exporting
- Skinned mesh rendering Animation motion matching Animation retargeting 2D rigidbody physics
- Physically based rendering Deferred shading Shadow mapping Signed distance field rendering
- Marching cubes Jump flooding Text rendering Input handling
- Sound integration Custom file format serialization

Music Player C#

Audio playback ● ID3 tag editor ● Asynchronous file loading ● SQLite

Education

GCSE O Level English, Mathematics, Economics, Fine Art, Biology

Qualifications NCFE Level 2 Certificate in Understanding Climate Change and Environmental Awareness, NCFE Level Certificate in Quality and Diversity, NVQ Level 2 Certificate in Customer Services

Interests

Favourite Games Halo: Combat Evolved Ninja Gaiden Black The Elder Scrolls Series Dark Souls 3 Bloodborne Sekiro: Shadows Die Twic

Sekiro: Shadows Die Twice

Burnout Revenge

Hobbies
Film and cinema
Photography
Video editing
Drawing
Novels
Fantasy
Sci-fi
Bouldering
Hiking